CURRICULUM VITAE

AIYEDERO MERCY OLUWASEUN

Telephone: +234 8163489185; E-Mail: mercyaiyedero@gmail.com

Career Goal:

To become a leading researcher and advocate in Veterinary Medicine, advancing the field through innovative research, compassionate care, and education.

Career Objective:

A highly motivated veterinary professional with a Doctor of Veterinary Medicine (DVM) and a strong research background in food safety and antimicrobial resistance. With a keen interest in public health and infectious diseases, I aim to leverage my microbiology and hygiene practices expertise to advance research and develop effective preventive measures. Committed to bridging the gap between scientific research and practical applications to enhance community health.

EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS ATTENDED WITH DATES

• University of Abuja, FCT, Nigeria	2017 - 2024
• Teacher Home International College Lokoja, Kogi State	2011 - 2017
• The Lord's Army Nursery and Primary School, Lokoja	2006 - 2011
ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS OBTAINED WITH DATES:	
Doctor of Veterinary Medicine	2024
•Senior Secondary School Certificate [WAEC & NECO]	2017
 First School Leaving Certificate [FSCL] 	2011
Diploma in Food Safety	2024

WORKING EXPERIENCE

- Sales girl: Rehoboth Specialist Hospital- August 2017 to February 2018
- **Industrial Training:** Student trainee at Veterinary Service Department, Ministry of Agriculture, Kogi State- April 2019- July 2020
- •Veterinary Intern: Felele Abattoir, Lokoja, Kogi State- April 2021
- **Student worker as Laboratory Attendant:** Student Employment Scheme (SES)-20th February 2020 to 21st December, 2023
- Veterinary Assistant Intern: Good Hands Veterinary Clinic (March 2024 September 2024)
- •Veterinary Doctor: Gwagwalada Abattoir 2024-till date

SKILLS/ ABILITY

- Computing Skills: Ability to process documents effectively using Microsoft Word & **PowerPoint**
- •Good Communication skills: Ability to communicate fluently and clearly in English
- Ability to work with a team toward problem solving

SEMINAR & TRAINING ATTENDED

- Female Inspires_ University of the West of Scotland (UWS): One Day Seminar for female students in Science Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM)
- Adamore Nigeria Limited- Technical Seminar 10th Feb, 2023

AWARDS/Distinction

Most outstanding student worker	2022/2023 SES year
Most dedicated student worker in Histology Laboratory	2020/2021 SSES year
Most punctual student worker in Histology Laboratory	2020/2021 SSES year
Best graduating student worker in Histology Laboratory	2020/2021 SES year
Best behaved student worker in Histology Laboratory	2020/2021 SES year
• Academic star of the year	2023
• Certificate of Excellence: Association of Veterinary Medical	2022
Student	2023

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH PROJECT

Bacteriological Assessment of Food Contact Surfaces of Canteens at the University of Abuja, Nigeria.

GRANTS

Undergraduate Research Grant- Assessment of the hygienic condition of Food Canteens at the University of Abuja- (2022)

Nigeria Veterinary Medical Association and Farm Alert Vetpreneurship 101 Grant Awardee- (2024) Unity Bank Corpreneurship Challenge Grant- (2024)

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Paper

Aiyedero, M.O., Adah, B.M.J., Oyelowo-Abdulraheem, F.O., &Okonkwo, C.M. (2023). Assessment of Hygienic Condition of Food Canteens at the University of Abuja. Journal for Undergraduate Research, 1 (2): 20-38

ORGANIZATION	
National Veterinary Medical Association (Member)	February 2024- Present
Veterinary Association of Nigeria (Member)	February 2024- Present
International Veterinary Student Association (Member)	2020- 2023
One Health Club, University of Abuja	2021-2023
The Africa Education Initiative (NEF Club), Uni Abuja	2021-2023

RESEARCH SKILLS

- 1. Literature review
- 2. Data collection
- 3. Data analysis

TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

- 1. Teamwork
- 2. Adaptability
- 3. Leadership skills
- 4. Time management
- 5. Problem solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- 1. Data analysis
- 2. MS Office skills
- 3. Research reporting skills

REFEREES

1. Prof. Nafarnda, Wesley Daniel (DVM, MVPH, PhD, FLEAD)

Department of Veterinary Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine,

University of Abuja, Nigeria

Email: wesley.nafarnda@uniabuja.edu.ng

nafarnda@gmail.com

08139778581, 08057125860

2. Dr. Adah Bridget Jessica

Department of Veterinary Microbiology Faculty of Veterinary Medicine University of Abuja,

Nigeria

Email: bridget.adah@uniabuja.edu.ng

08033506676